Guide to the Irene Kahn Collection ARCH071
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Irene Kahn Collection
1917 - 1996
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH071
1.29 Linear Feet (4 containers)
The collection contains a variety of professional and personal items including correspondence, memorabilia, and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Existence and Location of Copies
Some portions of the collection have been digitized, and can be accessed at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu/explore/explore/?c=allcollections:87.
Biographical Note
Irene Kahn born Irene Cohen, the daughter of Latvian immigrants. She used the name Irene Kahn as an adult and continued to use that name after her marriage to Samuel Berkman. Kahn, who joined the Hartt faculty in 1924, was a professor of piano, theory, and opera. She also taught at both St. Joseph's College and the University of Connecticut. She was remembered as the driving force behind many Hartt productions and within the University community. Kahn passed away in April 20, 1996, shortly after celebrarting her 92nd birthday.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains a variety of professional and personal items including correspondence, memorabilia, and photographs. Many of the photographs are of Kahn and her family members, particularly her husband and Hartt Professor Samuel Berkman, as well as of colleagues, students, and visiting performers. Many of the photographs have inscriptions and autographs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by filename.
Photographs; Correspondence; University of Hartford -- Employees; Berkman, John; Berkman, Samuel; Hartt College of Music; Julius Hartt School of Music; Kahn, Irene
- Annhurst College, 1966 May (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 4)
- Arrangements, Compositions, Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Aspen Institute, 1938 - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Berkman, John, 1941 - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
- Correspondence, 1966 - 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence/Jacobs, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Deidemia, 1946 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 9)
- Drawings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ear Training, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- European Tour, 1962 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 13)
- Irene Kahn Scholarship, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous, 1921 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1962 - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Note Cards, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Obituaries, 1965, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Photographs, 1944-1981, undated (Box 2, Folder 1 - 19)
  Conditions Governing Access
  One folder (Box 2, folder 19) in the file can only be opened by staff. The photograph inside is adhered to a glass pane. The edges are sharp and should not be handled without proper gloves.
- Programs, 1938 - 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1 - 4)
- Published Articles, Histories, Office of Dean, 1960 - 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook, 1917 - 1968, undated (Box 4)
- Script/Flagstaff, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Vitae, 1931 - 1938 (Box 3, Folder 7)